(The Shadow Sovereign)
You have never stayed overnight at my residence.
You sound like you know me pretty well.
You're always suspicious of me and Shen Xiao.
Do you want me to get caught
so you can make room for your new mistress?
Li Shu.
If I didn't know you hated me,
I would've thought
that you were just jealous.
Let go of me!
How did it come to this between us?
Let go!
Let go of me!
That was in the past. Why keep bringing it up?
I'm not the one who saved Shen Xiao.
You're blaming the wrong person.
I'm tired.
Just go.
Get some rest.
He insulted you on your wedding night.
He even kept a mistress.
What's so shocking about that?
Isn't every man like this?
Does that make it okay?
Even if it's not okay, does that mean it'll never happen?
Do you still care about the Prince Consort?
No.
Since you are done and divorced, why are you still involved with him?
Who do you think you are?
You are just a male companion.
You think you have any say in my life?
What if I don't want to be just your male companion?
Are you crazy?
Did you not hear what I said?
Just do your job and stay out of trouble!
Like I don't have enough trouble already?
I get it.
You and the Prince Consort aren't like normal couples.
Only when the Crown Prince falls,
will you finally be free.
Whatever I need to do,
I'll do it all.
That Shen scoundrel...
No. Censor Shen really is something else.
I thought
it was Censor Shen who stole your heart.
But now, it looks like
it's you who gave your heart away.
What nonsense are you spouting?
Your Highness, are you having a headache again?
Without Censor Shen here tonight, are you going to have nightmares again?
How about I call Censor Shen back for you?
He works better than any medicine.
What Censor Shen?
He's just Shen the scoundrel.
A meddling fool who can't mind his own business!
Seventh Prince Qin has traveled across the realm,
bringing treasures as tribute.
His Majesty is pleased,
thus inviting officials and royal kin to join the celebration
to share His Majesty's grace.
I have returned from my journey and prepared three gifts
to present to you, Father.
This is the first gift.
The finest rice harvested this year
from Wanming Granary in Jiangnan.
Every grain is as pure as jade.
Guanzhong suffered a drought earlier.
I was concerned when I heard about it.
So I brought this rice as tribute.
May our Ye Dynasty enjoy a bountiful harvest.
The drought in Guanzhong.
This rice is truly a good omen.
Excellent.
Father, this is the second gift.
I passed through Longxi
and found an ancient, nameless stele,
engraved with a folk song passed down for centuries,
praising the love of parents,
and wishing peace for home and the state.
I made a rubbing and present it to you.
May Father
enjoy a prosperous and long life in good health.
This gift is simple and sincere.
My son is truly thoughtful.
Father, please look at the last gift.
This last gift
is the Ye Dynasty Illustrated Almanac.
After leaving the palace, I traveled throughout Ye.
I documented every mountain, river, and city I saw,
along with the customs and local products in this almanac.
Although the almanac is complete,
it still needs some refining.
Please allow me
to stay at Qianfo Temple to focus on completing the illustrations.
So I can soon present it to you, Father.
Very good.
Such magnificent landscapes are all captured by my son.
Issue the decree.
Bestow upon Seventh Prince Li Qin
ten bars of tribute ink from the West
and 100 bolts of tribute silk.
He is permitted to walk before the throne.
You can stay at the Tranquil Room at Qianfo Temple
to focus on finishing the almanac.
All expenses
will be covered by the inner court.
Thank you for your grace, Father.
Seventh Brother vanished for ten years without a word.
Now, you've suddenly returned,
making everyone see you in a whole new light.
Thank you for the compliment.
I am of little use to the nation.
I can only do small and insignificant things.
Alright.
Then finish the almanac well.
Don't let Father down.
Yes, Brother.
Compared to mine,
the landscapes you painted have an even grander aura.
Three gifts brought you back before the throne.
So these ten years have been worth it.
For now, just focus on your cultivation at Qianfo Temple.
Wait until Shen Xiao pits the Crown Prince
against the Second Prince and both are weakened,
then you'll return to court.
I have no doubts about your plan.
It's just that
don't you intend to share our plan with Shen Xiao?
I recommended him to you back then.
But now, we've put him in danger by himself.
I feel uneasy about it.
We see each other as close friends.
But we've kept this a secret
from him all this while.
You recommended him to me.
But you didn't know he did plenty of ruthless things for his career.
He has a calculative mind, and he acts decisively.
If his goals align with ours,
he'll eventually find out about your identity.
What if his goals don't match ours?
You're meant to sit on the throne one day.
You can't let personal feelings hold you back.
But I promise you
that I'll spare his life.
Remember.
No matter who gets hurt along the way,
we can't let anything stop us from reaching our goal.
I understand.
He's the cursed child who killed his own mother during birth.
Father has always seen him as a jinx.
He's never attended the court for a single day.
I just don't believe
that he can turn the tables with just these three worthless gifts.
Could it be
that he's here to fight me for the throne
like Second Brother?
Ridiculous.
It's too much of a coincidence for Seventh Prince
to return to the capital now,
He showed up just as Shen Xiao appeared.
It's definitely not a coincidence, Your Highness.
Does he have connections with Shen Xiao?
Or has he come back
to help Second Brother?
Now Shen Xiao and Second Prince are clearly looking for your wrongdoings.
Luckily, we're prepared.
As for Seventh Prince,
he has no foundation at court yet.
He's not a threat for now,
but we should still remind the elders at court
so they don't get any ideas about him.
It's time these people get a wake-up call.
My birthday banquet in three days
will be the perfect opportunity.
I've invited all of you here today
not just for my birthday celebration.
It's because the nation is facing a disaster now.
The Eastern Palace will set up a relief granary
to support the nation when needed.
To set an example,
the Eastern Palace will donate 100,000 piculs of grain first.
I hope everyone will join in.
This...
(What's all this about preparing for national crisis?)
(The Crown Prince is taking advantage of Le Sheng's return)
(to invite all the neutral officials here using this birthday banquet.)
(He just wants to tie the noble families down)
(and show off to Father.)
The Zheng family is willing to support your cause.
You have my support too.
You have the Sang family's support.
You have the Ding family's support too.
You have the Bai family's support too.
You have my support.
- You have my support too. - I'll support you.
May I ask, will the grains for the relief granary
be managed by the Ministry of Revenue
or should we follow the Eastern Palace's command?
Second Brother,
are you questioning my loyalty?
Your Highness's devotion to the nation and its people is evident.
I, Shen Xiao,
have specially come here to wish the Crown Princess prosperity and health.
I heard the Crown Princess is donating grains to build a granary.
I admire your benevolence for the people.
So, I've specially brought you a birthday gift.
- What's that smell? - It's a rice sack.
This is clearly dirt.
How dare you insult me?
It's not an insult. This is the reality among the people.
The grains people buy from officials now
are mixed with dirt and husks.
Doesn't this show you
the urgency of building a relief granary?
You arrogant brat.
- Seize him! - My fellow officials.
Have you heard the cries of the people outside?
Your Highness!
Bad news. The refugees have blocked the gates upon hearing
the Crown Princess is giving out porridge at her birthday banquet.
This is rebellion!
We can't investigate any further.
The Crown Prince has stalled the Yongtong Canal's construction.
He's trying to bring down the Ministry of Revenue.
To build the canal, we need to distribute the grains.
We can't stall any longer.
Grains? Where are we supposed to get grains from?
Can we use the military grains from Taicang?
The royals, noble families, and honored officials
have surplus grains.
The only way is to collect grains from them
to break the Crown Prince's plan.
Then the Yongtong Canal can be built.
And the people can be saved.
Collecting grains?
Taking food from the mouths of nobles and officials
is basically cutting yourself off from the court.
No one would do that.
I'm willing to do that.
But I need an imperial decree.
To get that decree,
I have to borrow some support from the Crown Prince first.
This is rebellion!
Back up!
Move aside!
What are you doing? Are you rebelling?
Back up!
Please, have mercy. My child is starving to death.
Please have some mercy, noble ones.
Please, have mercy.
Noble one, just give me a bowl of porridge.
I'm begging you.
Please help us.
Go away!
Anyone trespassing in the residence
will be treated as a rioter.
They're citizens,
not rioters.
Didn't the Crown Prince set up this banquet of love
to help the people?
That's right. Today's banquet is meant to aid the disaster victims.
Guards, set up the porridge stalls.
Thank you, noble one.
The imperial decree has arrived!
Shen Xiao of the Ministry of Revenue, accept this decree.
I am pleased with the Crown Princess's disaster relief birthday banquet.
I hereby order Shen Xiao, the censor of the Ministry of Revenue,
to collect grains with this decree.
From princes and nobles downward,
all those of high rank
with 1,000 piculs as salary,
must donate according to their means
to meet the urgent needs of the nation.
We are at a difficult time.
People's lives are at stake.
Helping the nation in hardship shows true loyalty.
May you all understand my kind intentions
and work together for this cause.
Do not betray the court's favor.
So decreed.
I, Shen Xiao, accept the decree.
Shen Xiao is ordered to collect grains.
Have you heard about that?
(I haven't just heard about it.)
(I haven't seen him for half a month.)
(It's kept me up at night lately.)
I have heard a bit about it.
I heard Shen Xiao
has been visiting all the noble families recently.
But with little success.
So far, the grains collected
are less than 50,000 piculs.
Less than 50,000 piculs?
Shen Xiao
is not just collecting grains for Yongtong Canal.
It's also for me.
These people
are humiliating me.
I want you
to lead the grain donation for Shen Xiao.
You're my daughter,
and a member of the Cui family.
You are close to the Eastern Palace.
If you take action,
the noble families and royals
will understand my intentions.
You have the richest estate with tens of thousands of piculs.
It won't affect you.
Father,
my estate
is the same as Princess An Le's.
How would
An Le know the court's hardships?
She can't compare to you.
Yes, Father.
(Looks like Father wants to use me)
(to warn the Crown Prince and the noble families.)
Xiao Que, don't run!
Xiao Que.
Stop running.
- Your Highness. - Please spare me, noble one!
Please spare me, noble one!
What's wrong, Xiao Que?
I said I'd teach her to read, and she ran out.
Noble one, I don't want to learn to read.
A Gui secretly learned a few words,
and her master gouged out her eyes.
You saved me.
I'll work for you like a horse or ox.
Don't make me study.
Low-borns.
Where is your master now?
When we were fleeing, our master died of illness.
Grandma brought me here while escaping.
She starved to death too.
I see.
According to Ye law,
only those above commoner status can learn to read and write.
If someone of low-born status learns to read or write,
it's considered overstepping their place.
No wonder you're so scared.
From today on,
I'll remove your low-born status.
You can learn to read and write now.
Really?
Of course.
A princess never goes back on her word. She wouldn't lie.
Let's head to the study.
Thank you, noble one!
Get up.
Let's go. Let's head to the study.
Xiao Que, that's the wrong way.
This way.
Come on. This way.
She's just like a little sparrow.
That's why they call me Xiao Que.
Grandma says I'm clever.
That's why I always manage to get food.
Otherwise, I'd have starved to death long ago.
From now on, we won't have to fight for food.
Are you really going to take her home?
Nobles look down on those from humble families,
the newly rich look down on commoners,
and commoners look down on the low-borns.
But the low-borns
aren't even considered people.
Are we really any better?
We're just low-borns in the palace.
Le Sheng.
This world is rotten to the core.
So it's time for a change.
His Majesty ordered me to donate grains to Shen Xiao.
They are forcing you instead of pressuring the Crown Prince.
Isn't that making you openly oppose the Crown Prince?
I've always been just a pawn.
To Father and the Crown Prince, it's all the same.
Before the Crown Prince loses His Majesty's favor,
I have to donate these grains.
Do you have a perfect plan?
No. But after walking on thin ice for so long,
I've gained some experience and learned to strategize.
Shen Xiao has gone around to collect grains.
It's time he came to my doorstep.
I'll use him to make a risky move.
It'll help me keep His Majesty's favor,
and strike at the Eastern Palace.
Ladies, this peony is mine now.
- That's some big talk. - Yeah.
The princess is here. You can't win.
Enough with the chatter. Go ahead and pull the bow.
- Embarrassed now, aren't you? - Exactly.
- Let me try. - You're not even as good as me.
I'm definitely better than you.
Your Highness.
Xiao Que.
What are those nobles doing?
They're threading flowers and testing their hearts.
Inside that flower ball, there's a peony.
When the peony blooms, it outshines all other flowers.
Every other beauty bows before it.
That peony is today's prize.
Your Highness, what are you even saying?
That's awesome.
I want to be a scholar too.
I want to be that amazing.
(Scholars)
(have to read tons and tons of books.)
(The mountains and rivers on maps, )
(the customs in travel journals, )
(and the rise and fall in history books.)
(I learned these things back then just to survive)
(by becoming the Crown Prince's study companion)
(and copying books for him.)
Then I'll teach you to read and write myself from now on.
Thank you, Your Highness, my benefactor.
Good girl. Get up.
Your Highness, Censor Shen has requested an audience.
Censor Shen.
Is that Censor Shen?
Your Highness, Censor Shen has arrived.
Oh, it's him.
He really is handsome.
He's the noble who saved me together with the Princess.
Your Highness, I've brought the grain collection decree.
I'm here to collect grain from you.
So, it's about grain collection.
What's going on?
I didn't expect Censor Shen to come in person.
- He even came to the Xianke Bordello to collect grains. - Right?
He has come all the way here.
It's been ages since we last met.
And now that we finally meet,
do you have to hit me with such a buzzkill topic?
- Top Scholar is getting shy. - What's going on?